<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docs on What Bird Is That?</title>
    <link>/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docs on What Bird Is That?</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020, David Walters.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 12:32:19 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A first-pass response to the 10 principals</title>
      <link>/docs/10x/a-first-pass-response-to-the-10-principals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 12:32:19 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/10x/a-first-pass-response-to-the-10-principals/</guid>
      <description>10 Global Principals   Accelerate business priorities
 This is backwards. Priorities are to be clarified and then focus must be maintained. Acceleration is not something you &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo; in enterprise. Mass is mass, it moves as it moves. To give the appearance of &amp;ldquo;acceleration&amp;rdquo;, mass must be reduced. This is achieved by identifying waste - at all levels - and removing it.
   decisions in context of whole enterprise and ruse where possible</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Books to Read</title>
      <link>/docs/architecture-books-to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 14:20:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/architecture-books-to-read/</guid>
      <description>Ahead in the Cloud: Best Practices for Navigating the Future of Enterprise IT by Stephen Orban
 “Cloud computing is the most significant technology development of our lifetimes. It has made countless new businesses possible and presents a massive opportunity for large enterprises to innovate like startups and retire decades of technical debt. But making the most of the cloud requires much more from enterprises than just a technology change. Stephen Orban led Dow Jones’s journey toward digital agility as their CIO and now leads AWS’s Enterprise Strategy function, where he helps leaders from the largest companies in the world transform their businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: Solutions Architect - Associate Exam (SAA-002)</title>
      <link>/docs/aws/well-architected/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 01:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/aws/well-architected/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Well-Architected Framework Top level PDF
The Five Pillars of a Well-Architected Solution:  Resillient Performant Secure Cost-Optimised Operationally Excellent  Each pillar of the Well-Architected framework constitutes a domain of the Solutions Architect - Associate exam.
   Domain % of Examination     Design Resillient Architectures 34%   Define Performant Architectures 24%   Specify Secure Applications and Architectures 26%   Design Cost-Optimised Architectures 10%   Define Operationally Excellent Architectures 6%     Each domain of the examination is made up of objectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudformation Notes</title>
      <link>/docs/aws/cloudformationnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 22:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/aws/cloudformationnotes/</guid>
      <description>Cloudformation notes Continuous Delivery (Devops)  Infrastructure Continuous Delivery Using AWS Cloudformation   Use the intrinsic function Fn:Sub in YAML.   Use Changesets to preview the changes to infrastructure that will occur on update of a stack or stacks.   Use cross-stack references to share information between independent stacks:   Nested stacks for template re-use   Considerations for Exports and Nested Stacks   Sample Application   Examine a sample application   Microservices Application based on Amazon ECS    Sample code for the application can be found here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10x Notes for Phil Gadzinski</title>
      <link>/docs/10x/10x-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/10x/10x-notes/</guid>
      <description>Three Key Questions:
 Domain Driven Design - microservices API environment  a. Applying the strangler pattern b. The reverse Conway
1. AWS Cloud Apoption Maturity whitepaper  Cloud Adoption through containerisation
 shared responsibility model (whitepaper)    Serverless function - logic apps
 serverless vs stepfunctions    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>