<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on What Bird Is That?</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on What Bird Is That?</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020, David Walters.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 04:34:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the ultimate list of vscode extensions</title>
      <link>/posts/ultimate-vscode-extension-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 04:34:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ultimate-vscode-extension-list/</guid>
      <description>The ultimate list of VS Code Extensions  aaron-bond.better-comments adpyke.codesnap akmittal.hugofy AlanWalk.markdown-toc alefragnani.Bookmarks alefragnani.project-manager alexkrechik.cucumberautocomplete amazonwebservices.aws-toolkit-vscode aprilandjan.ascii-tree-generator arcsine.chronicler ArgyleWolfLabs.vscode-groovy Atishay-Jain.All-Autocomplete auchenberg.vscode-browser-preview austin.code-gnu-global aws-amplify.aws-amplify-vscode aws-scripting-guy.cform bajdzis.vscode-database be5invis.toml bibhasdn.unique-lines bierner.emojisense bierner.github-markdown-preview bierner.markdown-checkbox bierner.markdown-emoji bierner.markdown-mermaid bierner.markdown-preview-github-styles bierner.markdown-yaml-preamble blackmist.LinkCheckMD bpruitt-goddard.mermaid-markdown-syntax-highlighting budparr.language-hugo-vscode bungcip.better-toml christian-kohler.npm-intellisense christian-kohler.path-intellisense chrmarti.regex CodeStream.codestream codezombiech.gitignore CoenraadS.bracket-pair-colorizer CoenraadS.bracket-pair-colorizer-2 cssho.vscode-svgviewer ctf0.macros DanielThielking.aws-cloudformation-yaml darkriszty.markdown-table-prettify DavidAnson.vscode-markdownlint dawhite.mustache dbaeumer.jshint dbaeumer.vscode-eslint DmitryDorofeev.empty-indent docsmsft.docs-article-templates docsmsft.docs-authoring-pack docsmsft.docs-images docsmsft.docs-linting docsmsft.docs-markdown docsmsft.docs-metadata docsmsft.docs-preview docsmsft.docs-yaml donjayamanne.githistory DotJoshJohnson.xml eamodio.gitlens EditorConfig.EditorConfig eg2.vscode-npm-script esbenp.prettier-vscode evilz.vscode-reveal fabiospampinato.vscode-todo-plus felipecaputo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEST is a four letter word.</title>
      <link>/posts/test-is-a-four-letter-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 18:20:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/test-is-a-four-letter-word/</guid>
      <description>These days it is so easy to tie ourselves up in knots with one simple word. Testing is something that ought to be a part of the fabric of the delivery cycle, the skein of the SDLC.
Analysts should be testing their requirements against both the business and the delivery teams, frequently asking &amp;ldquo;is this what you want?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;can you build this?&amp;rdquo; so as to gain rapid feedback about the direction they are leading the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerate Data Collection</title>
      <link>/posts/data-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 14:20:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/data-collection/</guid>
      <description>Considerate Data Collection Isolating the task of collection. Survey data has some interesting properties, when you look at it up close. Survey data has a .size property, which is the (eventual?) size of the collection, called a population or sample. A population can be obtained from 1..n samples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Script the world</title>
      <link>/posts/applied-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 14:20:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/applied-devops/</guid>
      <description>Applied Devops Script the world Software entities typically evolve through a common set of phases:
 1. Design 2. Construct 3. Race 4. Crash 5. Repair 6. goto 3 Early devops used the scripting of infrastructure to propel software at low friction and low variance, achieving unprecedented levels of control and reliability.
Devops reaches further than just the infra team. It connects all disciplines  Devops thinking brought &amp;lsquo;master == prod&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliable, Evolving, Agile, Lean</title>
      <link>/posts/real-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/real-blog/</guid>
      <description>./realblog Reliable Evolving Agile Lean  Warning: Star Wars Quotes
 Software that survives. A lot of software today is not given a chance to survive. It&amp;rsquo;s written up, posted on the web, and taken down all within days. This kind of code is &amp;lsquo;firefly code&amp;rsquo; and sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s what we need to get our message across. We know it&amp;rsquo;s only just barely working. We have factored that into our plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>!00% Coverage is only the beginning</title>
      <link>/posts/code-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 14:20:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/code-coverage/</guid>
      <description>100% Coverage is only the beginning Code coverage gives us a solid foundation for delivery confidence, but it&amp;rsquo;s not the only way to boost delivery confidence. Confidence: the goal of a quality-focused delivery team. Code confidence is attained through rigorous and frequently repeated testing of the system against a raft of behavioural expectations.
These expectations form the specifications of the system and in fact document the system: both the functioning system, and the desires of the business that commissioned the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>/posts/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent Go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in Go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using Go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Go to Hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the Hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>